My first love was for the night sky.
[AI] 我的初恋是夜空。
Love is complicated.
[AI] 爱情是复杂的。
You're looking at a fly-through of the  Hubble Space Telescope Ultra-Deep Field.
[AI] 你看到的是哈勃太空望远镜超深场的飞行。
one of the most distant images of our universe ever observed.
[AI] 这是迄今为止观测到的最遥远的宇宙图像之一。
Everything you see here is a galaxy.
[AI] 你在这里看到的一切都是一个星系。
comprised of billions of stars each.
[AI] 由数十亿颗恒星组成。
And the farthest galaxy is  a trillion. trillion kilometers away.
[AI] 最远的星系是一万亿。万亿公里之外。
As an astrophysicist. I have the awesome privilege of studying
[AI] 作为一名天体物理学家。我有学习的殊荣
some of the most exotic objects  in our universe.
[AI] 我们宇宙中一些最奇异的物体。
The objects that have captivated me  from first crush throughout my career
[AI] 在我的整个职业生涯中，第一次迷恋的对象吸引了我
are supermassive.  hyperactive black holes.
[AI] 你是超级巨星。极度活跃的黑洞。
Weighing one to 10 billion times  the mass of our own sun.
[AI] 重量是我们太阳质量的1到100亿倍。
these galactic black holes  are devouring material.
[AI] 这些银河系黑洞正在吞噬物质。
at a rate of upwards of  1.000 times more than your "average"  supermassive black hole.
[AI] 以比你的“平均”超大质量黑洞高出1000倍的速度。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
These two characteristics.
[AI] 这两个特点。
with a few others. make them quasars.
[AI] 和其他一些人。让它们成为类星体。
At the same time. the objects I study
[AI] 同时我研究的对象
are producing some of the most powerful particle streams ever observed.
[AI] 正在产生一些有史以来观察到的最强大的粒子流。
These narrow streams. called jets.
[AI] 这些狭窄的小溪。叫喷气机。
are moving at 99.99 percent  of the speed of light. and are pointed directly at the Earth.
[AI] 它们以99.99%的光速运动。并直接指向地球。
These jetted. Earth-pointed. hyperactive and supermassive black holes
[AI] 这些是喷气式飞机。土尖的。超活跃和超大质量黑洞
are called blazars. or blazing quasars.
[AI] 它们被称为blazars。或者燃烧的类星体。
What makes blazars so special is that they're some of the universe's
[AI] blazars之所以如此特别，是因为它们是宇宙的一部分
most efficient particle accelerators.
[AI] 最有效的粒子加速器。
transporting incredible amounts of energy throughout a galaxy.
[AI] 在整个星系中输送难以置信的能量。
Here. I'm showing an artist's conception of a blazar.
[AI] 在这里我正在展示一位艺术家对布拉查的构思。
The dinner plate by which  material falls onto the black hole
[AI] 物质落入黑洞的餐盘
is called the accretion disc.
[AI] 被称为吸积盘。
shown here in blue.
[AI] 这里以蓝色显示。
Some of that material is slingshotted around the black hole
[AI] 其中一些物质被弹射在黑洞周围
and accelerated to insanely high speeds
[AI] 加速到了疯狂的高速
in the jet. shown here in white.
[AI] 在飞机上。此处显示为白色。
Although the blazar system is rare.
[AI] 虽然blazar系统很少见。
the process by which nature pulls in material via a disk.
[AI] 自然界通过圆盘吸入物质的过程。
and then flings some of it out via a jet. is more common.
[AI] 然后用喷气式飞机把它扔出去。这种情况更为普遍。
We'll eventually zoom out of  the blazar system
[AI] 我们最终将缩小blazar系统
to show its approximate relationship to the larger galactic context.
[AI] 显示它与更大的银河系背景的近似关系。
Beyond the cosmic accounting of what goes in to what goes out.
[AI] 超越宇宙对什么进入什么输出的解释。
one of the hot topics in  blazar astrophysics right now
[AI] blazar天体物理学目前的热门话题之一
is where the highest-energy  jet emission comes from.
[AI] 是能量最高的喷射源。
In this image. I'm interested in where this white blob forms
[AI] 在这幅图中。我感兴趣的是这个白色斑点在哪里形成
and if. as a result. there's any  relationship between the jet
[AI] 如果。因此这架喷气式飞机之间有什么关系吗
and the accretion disc material.
[AI] 吸积盘材料。
Clear answers to this question
[AI] 这个问题的明确答案
were almost completely inaccessible until 2008.
[AI] 在2008年之前几乎完全无法进入。
when NASA launched a new telescope that better detects gamma ray light --
[AI] 当美国宇航局发射了一台能更好地探测伽马射线的新望远镜时--
that is. light with energies a million times higher
[AI] 就是。能量高出一百万倍的光
than your standard x-ray scan.
[AI] 比你的标准x光扫描。
I simultaneously compare variations between the gamma ray light data
[AI] 我同时比较了伽马射线光数据之间的变化
and the visible light data from day to day and year to year.
[AI] 以及日复一日、年复一年的可见光数据。
to better localize these gamma ray blobs.
[AI] 为了更好地定位这些伽马射线斑点。
My research shows that in some instances.
[AI] 我的研究表明，在某些情况下。
these blobs form much closer to the black hole than we initially thought.
[AI] 这些斑点形成的距离黑洞比我们最初想象的要近得多。
As we more confidently localize
[AI] 随着我们更加自信地本地化
where these gamma ray  blobs are forming.
[AI] 这些伽马射线斑点形成的地方。
we can better understand how jets are being accelerated.
[AI] 我们可以更好地理解喷气式飞机是如何加速的。
and ultimately reveal  the dynamic processes by which some of the most fascinating objects in our universe are formed.
[AI] 最终揭示了我们宇宙中一些最迷人的物体形成的动力学过程。
This all started as a love story.
[AI] 这一切都是从一个爱情故事开始的。
And it still is.
[AI] 现在仍然如此。
This love transformed me from  a curious. stargazing young girl
[AI] 这种爱使我从一个好奇的人变成了一个好奇的人。凝视星空的少女
to a professional astrophysicist.
[AI] 给一个专业的天体物理学家。
hot on the heels of celestial discovery.
[AI] 紧跟着天体的发现。
Who knew that chasing after the universe
[AI] 谁知道追逐宇宙
would ground me so deeply to my mission here on Earth.
[AI] 会让我深深地感受到我在地球上的使命。
Then again. when do we ever know where love's first flutter will truly take us.
[AI] 再说一遍。什么时候我们才知道爱的第一次拍击会把我们带到哪里。
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）